Guide to the Douglas Crase and Frank Polach Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Douglas Crase research materials on Dwight Ripley and Rupert Barneby, 1896-2009; Series V
  - Books by others and assorted papers, 1896-2004
    - Books, notebooks, and catalogues, 1896-2004 (Box 61)
      Dwight Ripley. Poems, (Elkin Mathews & Marrot, 1931).; Dwight Ripley. Spring Catalogue: A Poem, (Weekend Press, 1952). Inscribed to Peggy Guggenheim by Dwight.; Peggy Guggenheim. Out of This Century: The Informal Memoirs of Peggy Guggenheim, (The Dial Press, 1946). Inscribed to Dwight from Guggenheim. Dwight helped write Out of this Century and the two also had a brief affair.; Max Ernst and Paul Éluard. Translated by Hugh Chisolm. Misfortunes of the Immortals, (Black Sun Press, 1943). With inscription to Dwight from Peggy Guggenheim.; Clement Greenberg. Joan Miró, (Quadrangle Press, 1948). Inscribed to Dwight and Rupert by the author.; Oscar Williams, ed. The War Poets: An Anthology of the War Poetry of the 20th Century, (John Day, 1945). Inscribed to Rupert by Willard Maas. Maas's love sonnet "Letter to Rupert' is published as "Letter to R," in The War Poets. The two had a love affair, 1943–?.; Willard Maas. Fire Testament, (Alecestis Press, 1935). With inscription by the author to Rupert.; Hugh Chisolm. Several Have Lived. Illustrations by André Masson, (The Gemor Press, 1942). With inscriptions from Hugh Chisolm to George Barker and from Barker to Williard Maas. Mass in turn gave the book to Dwight Ripley. It was then given to Rupert, who gave it as a gift to Frank Polach.; Card from Rupert Barneby to Frank Polach with provenance of Several Have Lived, 1991.; H. Stuart Thompson's Flowering Plants of the Riviera (1914). On the endpapers Dwight Ripley entered the itinerary for his and Rupert's Iberian trip, ca. 1935 along with lists of species that would hopefully be collected for the gardens back at Dwight's Sussex estate the Spinney. The book is a journal of their exploration and a record of species.; Janice C. Beatley. Vascular Plants of the Nevada Test Site and Central-Southern Nevada: Ecologic and Geographic Distributions, (1976). Inscription to Rupert from the author on card tipped in on f.f.e.; Waddy Thompson and Estelle Ross. A Graphic History of the United States for Young Readers (1920). With an inscription to Master Rupert Barneby.; The Published Writings of Philip Lutley Sclater, 1844–1896, (1896). With TLS, laid in, from Rupert Barneby on Stirling House Stationery, 1962, explaining that the books was passed on to him by his paternal grandmother, Sclater's sister.; T.P Barneby. European Alpine Flowers in Colour, (Nelson, 1967). Inscribed to Rupert and with ALS from the author.; C.L. Baldwin. Quinquivara. (Gemor Press, [1944]). 3 botany books with information on Rupert Barneby and Dwight Ripley.
    - Photographs of Louisa Geraldine (Ingham) Barneby, 1900-1949 (Box 62)
      3 photographs of Louisa Geraldine (Ingham) Barneby Rupert's mother sometimes called "Poppy."
    - Record of the Species ledger, 1941-1949 (Box 63)
      Dwight Ripley. "Record of Species," 1941–49. Bound ledger book with handwritten record of species found by Dwight and Rupert.
    - Rolodex rotary card file, 1970-1989 (Box 64)
      Rupert Barneby's Rolodex rotary card file.
    - Citations, plaques and awards and other material (Box 65)
      Citations, plaques and awards presented to Rupert Barneby; Paired photographs of Douglas Crase and Frank Polach along with photograph of Alfonso Ossorio sculpture (Rupert Barneby designed the arboretum at The Creeks, East Hampton, N.Y. where the sculptures were displayed. The photographs of Douglas and Frank were always displayed in Rupert's bedroom in his Botanical Garden loft. Polish language newspapers in which Dwight Ripley's poems were published during World War II; Other assorted items.
    - Citations, plaques and awards, 1960-1979 (Box 66)
      Citations, plaques and awards presented to Rupert Barneby.
    - Tufa (limestone) and tablet-sized platform, undated (Box 71 (Art))
      Tufa - Douglas writes of this piece of tufa in Both: "In Rupert's loft there were many curious objects. One that holds my attention in retrospect consisted of a tablet-sized platform, as for a bonsai arrangement, on which sat a porous gray rock that might have been the scale model of a malevolent asteroid. It was a chunk of tufa, the calcareous (as in limestone) deposit from springs and streams that is favored in the rock garden or in the alpine house by plants like Lepidium nanum, is coveted therefore by the rock gardener, and from which Rupert and Dwight constructed their rock-and-tufa cliff at the Spinney."
    - Large vasculum (container), 1941 (Box 70 (Art))
      The larger vasculum was used in 1941 and later when they discovered Cymopterus ripleyi and other plants in Nevada.
    - Small vasculum (container), 1939 (Box 76)
      The smaller and ornate vasculum was used by Dwight and Rupert on expeditions to Spain and North Africa prior to 1939. It held many samples, including Limonium asparagoides that brought back from Algeria.
  - Publications
    - Dwight Ripley and Rupert Barneby (Box 67)
    - Rupert Barneby (Box 68)
  - Artwork and other papers, 1925-1995
    - Other materials, 1953 (Box 73)
      Dylan Thomas Fund. Letter to Dwight Ripley. Dec. 8. 1953. In frame. Letter on Intercultural Publications Inc. stationery thanking Dwight for his "magnificent contribution to The Dylan Thomas Fund. Signed by Tennessee Williams, Thornton Wilder, Arthur Miller, Marianne Moore, W. H. Auden and Wallace Stevens.
    - Photographs, 1935; 1995 (Box 74)
      Barbara Ertter. Rupert Barneby with colleagues, Independence Mountains, Nevada, June 24, 1981. This is a framed copy print. According to Douglas this "is the only photo so far located of Rupert collecting with colleagues after Dwight's death."; Joan Leigh-Fermor. "House party in Sussex, 1935." Framed copy photograph from Clive Fisher, Cyril Connolly: The Life and Times of England's Most Controversial Literary Critic, (1995).
    - Drawing and photograph, 1944; circa 1950s (Box 77 (Oversize))
      John Button. "Nude portrait of Joe LeSeur" in frame, ca. early 1950s? Dylan Thomas Fund. Letter to Dwight Ripley. Dec. 8. 1953. In frame.; Unidentified photographer. "Dwight Ripley," photographic portrait taken at the Plaza Hotel, NYC, ca. 1944.
    - Ledger page, 1950 (Box 78)
      Tibor de Nagy Gallery ledger page, November–December 1950. Color facsimile in frame.
    - Sketches, 1925; 1937 (Box 79)
      Dwight Ripley. "Master Rupert Barneby at Harrow," 1925. Pencil sketch in frame. Peter Markham Scott. "Rupert Barneby," pencil sketch, 1937.